# **VLATKO EFREMOVSKI**

iOS Developer



vlatko.efremovski@gmail.com



in <u>vlatko-efremovski</u>



github.com/Svegjan



2282749/vlatko-svegjan



Naturally curious iOS developer with over 9 years of experience, having spent most of my time working at various companies and as an independent contractor. I have worked on a variety of projects, including CRM and telecom network apps, SAAS apps using Bluetooth tech, Enterprise apps, News/Marketing apps, and more.

For more details regarding my work experience, please view my portfolio

## Recent History

#### **Lead Mobile Developer**

The List

March 2022 - Present

Decreased churn rate of the Consumer app by 20% after implementing tracking metrics and setting up targeted campaigns.

Managed the development and release of the Seller App, by closely collaborating with stakeholders and merchants.

Improved communication lines between departments.

#### Lead iOS Developer

Upsales Nordic AB March 2018 - March 2022

> Spearheaded a major restructuring of the legacy CRM app and developed a brand new, improved and more scalable version of the app in Swift; increased user engagement - while leading a team of developers, utilizing an agile workflow.

Communicated with different clients to develop custom white-label versions of the app.

#### Co-founder & Mobile Developer

Enspyra Tech April 2016 - March 2018

> Managed a cross-functional team, ranging from mobile developers, digital marketers, content writers and collaborated with business development and data analysis operations.

> Led a mobile team in the development of News & Marketing Apps, improving the stability and scalability of the applications, prompting the increase of the user base.

### Education

#### Msc in Management of Information Systems

University American College Skopje 2012 - 2015

Thesis: "Implementation of Monetization Practices in Mobile Applications"

#### **BSc in Software Engineering**

University American College Skopje 2009 - 2012

Developed a system for a virtual medical office using ASP.NET technology together with SQL server 2008 as a graduation thesis.



#### **Swift**

Writing Swift full-time for 7+ years and closely following its evolution since 1.0. I follow the latest trends and keep up with the development of the iOS ecosystem, and, as of late, this includes the ever-so improving framework of SwiftUI.

#### Objective C

Prior to Swift, I was introduced to mobile development with Objective-C, with which I developed and worked on a multitude of different apps.

#### Communicating ideas

I have a special talent for breaking down complex topics and presenting them in an easy to understand manner.

I get immense fulfillment from mentoring and knowledge sharing.

## Other Skills

Mentoring and Managing UIKit, CallKit, SwiftUI CocoaPods / Carthage / SPM Agile and SCRUM methodologies Continuous Integration - CircleCI Jenkins, Bitrise

React-Native **Emotional Intelligence XCode** Git version control, Jira AdobeXD, Figma

MVC, MVP, MVVM

## **A** Interests

Football	Jogging	Crypto	Travel
Hiking	Books	Blockchain	LOTR

## Languages

Macedonian, English, Swedish Native or bilingual proficiency